KAITO - HARUKI
（介人 悠晖）
SHOU
（笑）
Why?
为什么？
Why is this happening?
为什么会发生这种事？
CLUB SHO-TIME
（俱乐部笑场）
Dad…
爸爸
Mom…
妈妈
Are you all right?
你还好吗？
You've really hung in there…
撑到现在 辛苦你了
There's nothing to be afraid of here.
在这里你什么都不用怕
Anyway, get some rest for now.
总之 先休息一下吧
Manager…
经理
They've come again.
它们又来了
I'm sorry!
抱歉！
There's a small meeting I need to attend.
我得去开个小会
Let's take the time to talk again later.
晚点再来找你聊
You can wait by yourself, can't you?
你一个人在这里等 没关系吧？
It'll be all right.
不会有事的
I'll definitely come back.
我一定会回来
It's a promise.
我保证
Okay.
好
Let's do this.
动手吧
Yeah!
好！
CLUB SHO-TIME THIRD GENERATION
（俱乐部笑场 第三代）
Hurry, give me another one!
快点 再给我一个！
Okay!
是！
Don't do it, Akemi! Stop--
别这样 明美！不要…
Damn it.
可恶
I wanted to become number one… just like Shou…
我想成为第一 就像阿笑那样…
Let's do whatever it takes to protect this place!
要不惜一切 全力死守！
Put some spirit into it!
大家拿出干劲来！
Yeah!
好！
Phew…
可算到了
It's been a while since I was last here, but…
虽然有好一阵子没来了 不过…
Shinjuku is just as I expected it to be.
果然不出我所料
It's really packed here.
新宿可真热闹呀
But, I know you wouldn't just lay down and die!
但我知道 你是绝对不会坐以待毙的
Wait for me, Kencho!
等我 阿宪！
Now that I've quit, I can grow any kind of beard I want.
既然都已经辞职 我可以随心所欲地蓄胡子了
I wonder if there's any way I can get it to grow in any cooler…
不知道怎样才能 让它看上去更酷一点…
MANLY ESSENTIALS
（男子汉必备）
Nope, no way.
这不行
I'm shaving it.
还是把胡子剃掉吧
9. WINE AND DINE A FLIGHT ATTENDANT 10. GROW A COOL BEARD
（九：跟空服员喝酒聚餐 十：蓄帅气的胡子）
What should I do today?
今天该干什么呢？
It's working!
快看看！
I've got messages!
我收到了短信！
The internet must be back up!
网络总算恢复了
Come to think of it, for the past three years,
话说 过去三年里
I was so bogged down with work that I've had to turn down invite after invite.
我一直埋头工作 一次又一次地拒绝各种邀约
BEEN FOREVER! YOU GOOD?
（好久不见！）
There're tons of people I want to see after all this time!
这么长时间了 我有好多想要见的人
QUIT MY JOB! NEED A SURF BUDDY?
（刚辞职 去冲浪吧？）
Oh, right.
原来如此
I can only use my phone now because internet traffic is down.
网络连接不上 我只能用手机通信
Which means there aren't as many people using it.
也就表示 我如今能联系上的人已经不多了
I sacrificed time I could have spent with friends, for what?
我牺牲跟朋友相聚的时间
What good did all that overtime do me?
加那么多班究竟是为了什么？
KENCHO
（阿宪）
You should just quit already!
你早该辞职了！
Kencho…
阿宪…
There's no way a guy like you would just lay down and die.
你这家伙绝对不会轻易丧命对吧！
I knew it. It's no good.
果然出不去
There's no way out!
我无路可逃了！
Nothing but water for three days.
连续三天只能靠喝水充饥
Worst of all…
最糟的是…
I've been stuck in here with this monster.
还有个怪物跟我一起困在这里
I'm losing my goddamn mind!
我快要疯了！
That said,
话虽如此
I'm glad my drunk ass just happened to pick the bondage room.
幸好我这醉鬼 恰好选了一个玩捆绑束缚的房间
Damn it.
可恶
I'm starving.
肚子好饿
And I'm so exhausted by all this.
我已经身心俱疲了
Is this how this all ends for me?
这就是我的结局吗？
In some stupid place like this?
死在这样一个破地方？
Hey, that's wild!
那也太夸张了吧！
-Why am I thinking of him now? -My sides hurt!
-为什么我现在会想到他？ -笑得我肝疼
Oh… that's right…
对了
You always laughed at my stupid jokes, didn't you?
你总会被我的蠢笑话逗笑 不是吗？
-Do it again! I want to film it! -Those were the days! In college…
-再来一次！我要录下来 -多么快乐的时光啊！大学时…
Is that you, Akira?
阿辉 是你吗？
Whoa! You picked up!
你接电话啦！
Kencho, you're alive!
阿宪 你还活着！
It's been a while!
好久不见
Has it really been a year since we last went out for drinks?
我们上次出去喝酒是什么时候 差不多一年前？
Yeah…
是啊
What's wrong?
怎么啦？
You sound down!
你听起来好没精神
Uh, well… why do you sound so hyped?
这个…你怎么听上去这么兴奋？
I'll tell you all about it when we meet!
等见面了我再慢慢跟你说！
Where are you right now?
你现在在哪儿？
I'm in Shinjuku.
我在新宿
Okay! Shinjuku! I'll be right over!
好的！新宿是吧！我马上过来
No, it's impossible.
没可能的
The place is swarming with zombies. Just forget about me!
这地方到处都是僵尸 你别管我了
It'll be fine! It'll be fine!
安啦！没事的
Anyway, text me your address!
总之 把你地址发给我吧
-Huh? You-- -Bye!
-什么？你… -回见！
Back in college, Kencho and I went through a lot together
上大学那四年 我和阿宪一起在橄榄球社团
during our four years in the rugby club.
经历了很多风风雨雨
He was a handsome, smooth talker.
他人长得帅 又能说会道
But despite being popular, he'd go all-out to be the life of the party.
不光受欢迎 还很愿意在人群中奉献自己活跃气氛
He was my closest friend.
他是我最好的朋友
He became a big-time real estate agent after college.
大学毕业后 他进了大公司成为房地产销售员
With his natural talent for communication,
他那与生俱来的交流天赋
things were smooth sailing for him at his job.
让他在那一行干得顺风顺水
Yesterday, I was entertaining some Diet members!
昨天我把一帮国会议员 哄得可开心了！
Those guys spend money on a whole other level!
那些家伙出手可是相当阔绰
Oh, that's right.
对了
Check out my new girlfriend.
看看我的新女朋友
She's a model!
是个模特哦
-Took a day trip to Paris last weekend. -Meanwhile…
-上周末我们刚去了巴黎一日游 -而那时的我
My soul was getting crushed in the gears of an exploitative corporation.
正在为黑心企业卖命搬砖 灵魂被逐渐摧毁
So I didn't have the patience to listen to other people's success stories.
我没有耐心听别人的成功故事
What's the deal with your company?!
你那家公司是怎么回事？
It's super exploitative!
那地方太压榨人了
Just walk away!
赶紧走吧
You should just quit already!
你早该辞职了
What the hell…
什么嘛
I'm seriously struggling, here.
我现在是真的很挣扎耶
My serious advice is that you should quit!
我也是真的建议你辞职呀
Staying with a company like that is stupid.
傻子才留在那种黑心企业呢
You're just an idiot!
你就是个傻子
And you're being obnoxious with all your bragging about your personal life!
你一直不停炫耀 自己的成功 真是烦死了
You should stop doing that!
快闭嘴吧！
Bartender!
老板！
Check please!
结账！
Wait for me, Kencho!
等我 阿宪
I'm on my way!
我这就来了！
So, this is the end, huh?
到此为止了吗？
Considering my life…
以我的人生来说
It's a pretty great way to go out.
就这么解脱了倒也不错
I'm sorry
对不起
I couldn't keep my promise.
我不能信守承诺了
What happened?
怎么回事？
Am I… safe?
我…得救了？
What's that noise?
那是什么声音？
All right!
好嘞
Okay!
好了
What's happening?
发生了什么事？
The zombies are gone?
僵尸全都走了？
What's going on here?
这是怎么回事？
Kencho…
阿宪
Akira…
阿辉
You really came.
你真的来了
Kencho!
阿宪！
You were right this whole time!
你说的都是对的
I should have just quit a company like that!
我早该离开那家黑心企业了！
But instead of listening to your advice…
但我却没有听你的话
I got jealous of how successful and happy you were.
因为我嫉妒你可以 那么成功、那么开心
I got annoyed and took my anger out on you!
我很不爽 所以就拿你撒气
Even though we're friends… I'm sorry!
尽管你是我的朋友…对不起！
I really am! I'm sorry!
真的很对不起！
You… came all this way
你不顾危险地跑过来就是为了
just to tell me that?
告诉我这些？
I'm really sorry!
真的很对不起
Well…
好吧
How should I say this?
该怎么说呢？
I should…
我也应该…
They're back!
僵尸回来了！
I shouldn't have shouted!
都怪我刚才喊那么大声
Our only chance is to go up!
上天台！那是唯一的出路
Kencho! Behind you!
阿宪 小心身后！
It's no good! It's not gonna hold!
情况不妙 这扇门撑不了多久
Hang in there!
坚持一下！
That won't be enough.
这样不足以抵挡
They'll get through soon!
他们很快就会冲进来
What should we do?
我们该怎么办？
Ugh, damn it!
可恶！
What should we do, Akira?!
阿辉 我们该怎么办？
Hey, Akira!
喂 阿辉！
We jump.
我们跳过去
The next building over is close enough to leap across.
隔壁大楼跟这里的间距足够近 我们可以跳过去
What? No way…
什么？不可能
We can't make that distance!
我们跳不了那么远
That's impossible!
没可能的
Hey… Akira?
喂…阿辉？
Guess we'll find out by jumping!
行或不行 得跳了才知道！
Akira!
阿辉！
Are you all right?!
你还好吗？
How'd you like that?!
怎么样 帅吧？
How'd I like it?!
什么怎么样？
You've got balls of steel, man!
你真是太勇猛了 兄弟！
Hurry up and get over here!
你也快跳过来！
Kencho?
阿宪？
Akira…
阿辉
I know you came all this way to save me, but I'm sorry.
难得你为了救我 大老远跑来 可是对不起
I don't think… I can jump that.
要跳过去…我做不到
Before the end, there's something I want to tell you, Akira.
在死之前 我有话想对你说 阿辉
The truth is…
其实
I didn't enjoy my job at all.
我一点也不喜欢我的工作
Day after day, I had to smile at people while lying to their faces.
日复一日 我都得微笑着欺骗客人
I tricked them into bad contracts.
忽悠他们签下糟糕的合同
The praise from the higher-ups, the company's acknowledgement…
即使因此得到 上级的称赞、公司的多次表扬
The gorgeous models I dated…
跟漂亮的模特约会
Dining out with big-time politicians and famous athletes…
跟政界大人物和知名运动员吃饭…
didn't make me happy at all.
我还是一点也开心不起来
Hey, Akira!
阿辉！
I was just showing off!
我当时就是死要面子！
I was just lying to myself to feel less empty inside.
我在自欺欺人 好让内心感觉没那么空虚
So, I pretended like I was having fun.
所以我假装快乐
I was a horrible person… always bragging!
我就是个一直在自吹自擂的烂人 ！
I'm the one who needs to say I'm sorry!
该道歉的人是我
I really am!
我真的
I'm sorry!
很抱歉！
Well, that makes sense.
好吧 那就说得通了
That fun-loving panache of yours
毕竟你的自我奉献精神
always came through to make sure we were all having fun!
就是总会尽力哄我们开心啊！
That's right!
对啊
I wanted a job where I could sincerely entertain my clients.
我想要一份能真心取悦客户的工作
I actually
我其实
wanted to be a stand-up comic!
想当一名谐星！
In that case…
这样的话
Just quit already and become one right now!
你现在就快辞职去当谐星吧！
Take it from me!
听我的准没错
You should always listen to your friends when they give you advice!
建议你要听取朋友的意见
If you're a stand-up comic, get ready and show me you can jump that distance!
是谐星的话 就做好豁出去的准备 让我看你跃过这道坎
Yeah!
好！
Hey, Akira! Give me a hand!
阿辉 快拉我一把！
This time, it isn't a joke!
这回可不是闹着玩的
Is this how I'm going to die?!
我要就这样死去了吗？
Completely buck naked?!
赤身裸体地归西？
Akira!
阿辉！
Up you go!
快上来！
What's the matter, Kencho?!
怎么了 阿宪？
Were you bitten by a zombie?
你被僵尸咬了吗？
I scraped… my balls!
我的蛋蛋刮伤了！
I didn't expect you to cry out like a baby.
没想到你会在那种时候 像个宝宝一样嚎啕大哭
And buck naked too…
而且还一丝不挂…
You idiot. It was highly sophisticated new material
你个白痴 刚那是我的全新笑点
inspired by my rebirth as an entertainer.
灵感来源于我重生为谐星的那一刻
New? You always do naked jokes.
哪里新了？你总爱开这种裸体的玩笑
I'll be doing that more often from here on.
从今往后我会更经常这么干
Oh man, I'd really like to stand on a stage.
天啊 我真想到舞台上表演看看
Hey, do you have any connections from work?
你工作上没什么可以动用的人脉吗？
Work? What's that? I've never done it.
工作？那是什么鬼？我从来没干过
Who's the one who looked like he was going to die from the exploitative company?!
之前是谁一脸 快被黑心企业摧残至死的样子呀？
You looked worse than the zombies!
你那副德性比僵尸还惨！
What the hell?
你才是
You?! A stand-up comic?!
你要当谐星表演脱口秀？
What kind of comic cries?
哪种秀是表演哭给人看的呀？
Anyway, you were seriously amazing today!
总之 你今天真的酷毙了！
Guys who quit their jobs, drop everything, and move on with their lives
毅然辞职、舍弃一切 在生活中勇往直前的人
tend to be really successful later on.
之后往往都会很成功的
Like entrepreneurs or artists…
比如很多企业家和艺术家
You might even be…
你甚至可能会是…
the guy who saves us all from the zombie infection.
在这场僵尸感染灾难中 拯救全人类的英雄呢
Me?
我吗？
No way. That's not gonna happen.
怎么可能？别开玩笑了
Yeah, probably not.
也对 大概不可能吧
That ain't happening.
根本不可能
Whoa, I just thought up a new bit!
我刚想到了一个脱口秀的点子！
It probably involves you getting naked, doesn't it?
八成是你裸体的桥段吧？
32. DRINK AND LAUGH 33. MEET DREAM WOMAN
（32：与好友喝酒谈笑到天亮）
Next time: Flight Attendant of the Dead.
下一集：死者与空服员